we have the management joining us of
isis lombard so for q1 numbers seem to
be better the profit has jumped this
time on the back of healthy growth and
premium income
i mean segment wise there's a sharp
reduction in loss ratios for health but
losses in the motor segment have gone up
gopal balachandran chief financial
officer and chief risk officer at
isis lombard general insurance is now
joining us to take us through uh some uh
some perspective kopal great to have you
with us here thank you very much for
your time could you just paint the
picture on both health and motor
both actually have proved to be pain
points for you for the last two years or
so
how how things looked in q1 and what is
the outlook going forward
so thanks thanks prashanth for having me
on the show i think uh if you look at uh
both of the segments have been uh
preferred segments for us
um i think if you look at motor in
specific over the last couple of years
we have seen a lot of challenges coming
around at the same time we have seen the
supply side construct constraints
impacting new vehicle sales
at the same
time we are also seeing possibly the
industry starting to see the benefit of
lower claim incidences because of peak
of covet waves when the number of
vehicles used on the roads were far
lower and hence all in all i think when
you look at the overall
uh segment on motor i think the growth
has been relatively subdued and the
competitive intensity therefore has been
at high ten levels from an isis lombard
standpoint not just now even in the past
i think the call that we have generally
taken whenever we see relatively higher
levels of competition has to be a bit
cautious which is why if you look at our
fi 22 numbers for the matter of fact we
actually kind of undergo the market when
it came when it comes to motor insurance
but as things are coming back in terms
of economic activities we are already
seeing increased number of claims
getting intimidated so the benefit of
lower claim insurances is pretty much
behind us and therefore if you look at
it from an industry standpoint the
industry is already operating at a
combined ratio on the motorcycle on the
one damage segment of 110 115
so therefore it does not become viable
since to operate at those levels of
combined ratios which is why from an
isis number standpoint we affected small
amount of price increases on the motor
segment particularly in the one damage
space since quarter four and it
continues as we speak so that's how we
are looking at positioning on the motor
segment and the
and the point that we have narrated to
the market is in a in a period when the
segment is significantly competitive we
would want to take a cautious stand and
our growth will be largely in line with
the industry growth so even for this
quarter if you see motor our growth has
been in line with industry with over 27
percent so when you
when you talk about industry growth
within motor what is the expectation for
fy23
so i think obviously when you look at
this number sonya i think there's
obviously a base effect as i mentioned i
think last two years has been periods of
relative softness
on account of multiple reasons that i
explained i think there is a clear
expectation that the growth momentum
should kind of come back as we speak and
when you talk to and i mean given the
fact that when you talk to the oems you
definitely see them talking about some
of the supply side constraints getting
eased out particularly towards the
second half of the year so therefore we
should definitely see growth coming back
particularly on the private car side
on two wheelers when we get to see the
demand of the ground is still not back
to normal again there is an expectation
that in the two-wheeler space we will
possibly see things coming back to
normalcy over the next i would say two
or three quarters so all in all the
expectation that we have on motor is
things should start to kind of look up
much better than what we had seen in the
last couple of years and from our
positioning from an isis number
standpoint as i said we will obviously
watch out for the levels of competitive
intensity and at this point of time the
call that we are kind of largely
directed to the market is to broadly
stay in line with industry growth but
our within motor different segments
could exhibit different levels of growth
for us
gopal what about health
yeah i was just kind of talking on
health prashanth i think health again
has been an area of focus for us now if
you look at the aggregate numbers again
for quarter one for ics number the
growth was quite handsome at about 33
if you look at the industry growth in
the aggregate was about 21
when i split this growth into corporate
and retail i think in line with what we
have been talking through on the
corporate health side since the last i
would say 9 to 12 months we have been
affecting price revisions on that space
of almost more than 20 plus and that is
done very well in so far as customer
retentions are concerned it is upwards
of 1995 percent retention is what we
have seen so that trend line is
continuing even as we speak okay on the
retail side i think again the growth in
the agency distribution where we're
investing has been very very positive we
had a growth of almost 18 in the agency
contribution this quarter and that's an
area where we're investing investing and
expanding distribution okay gopal uh
good morning you know uh
hdfc live yesterday confirmed the story
by uh michael josh that uh irdi has
asked life insurance companies to have
some targets
is it the same for general insurance as
well have they have spoken to you about
it
so i think anus that's a that's a good
point i think in general if you look at
the new regulator who has assumed the
chief was assumed office i think they
are significantly looking at increasing
penetration across different segments
and therefore they are asking companies
to look at
every segment of opportunity that one
can see and see as to how we can
increase penetration across the industry
as a whole and therefore each companies
have been asked to kind of go back and
look at what they can kind of
incrementally contribute and therefore
how we can uh kind of aid the insurance
penetration no so
so for life insurance i believe the
targets have been set but for general
insurance also there's there's some
discussion
so definitely there is a discussion in
terms of what growth that each company
as i said because the larger objective
is to kind of increase penetration and
therefore they are asking every company
to look at as to how they can
incrementally contribute to the growth
numbers so that the overall penetration
objective can be achieved yes there has
been a discussion around that it's been
the number for you for isis lombard
which is under discussion not the final
but what is the discu what is the number
so that's what i'm saying i think each
companies will have to kind of look at
what kind of growth numbers that one
will be exhibiting and they have clearly
asked us to look at the growth plans and
see as to how we can incrementally
contribute to the penetration there's a
number because for life our colleagues
reported specific numbers for each
company you know thirty percent
yeah
so that's what i'm saying i think
obviously one has looked at in terms of
what kind of growths that one has seen
over the past several periods and
relative to that i think they would
definitely want to see the growth
numbers significantly getting enhanced
so that as i said the overall insurance
prediction objective do you give growth
numbers or the growth numbers come from
the
regulator so at this point of time as i
said the regulator's objective is to
increase penetration and therefore they
want every company to contribute to that
okay and hence to that extent is what we
are also equally is there is there any
linking this growth target achieving or
not achieving two
other facets like
you know senior management compensation
etc which is another thing we picked up
and reported on
so i'm just saying there are a lot of
those developments that's happening in
the market at the end of the day the
larger objective that regulator is
driving is more in terms of the
development agenda
in terms of increasing penetration and
that's what one is largely focusing on
so that's on growth but the adia has
also been looking at reducing the
expenses of management and the
commissions that are paid on policies
right what is your ask here and do you
have any kind of road map on how you
would be looking to reduce it
so i think in general i think uh even
for isis lombard i think we always keep
looking at how the growth in management
expenses has been related to the growth
in revenues just to kind of put let's
say when you look at the quarter gone by
we had seen as you rightly mentioned we
had a growth sonya of almost in premiums
of almost about 30 percent now visibly
that if you look at the growth in the
management expenses has been a shade
lower and about 27.8
so that's something that we always keep
looking for and and not just for a
quarter if you look at over a last
14-year cycle from 2008 to 2022. in
general i think what we have seen in so
far as our head count productivity has
been a kaggar of almost equal to 14 15
so that's an area which you
significantly focus on in terms of
keeping the overall cost of distribution
under check and equally yes it is also
the regulator's thrust that when you are
kind of significantly embarking on
growth we will you also have to kind of
keep the overall management expenses
under uh check as well so that's an area
where we are kind of investing in which
is why if you look at it for from our
digitized digital capability whether it
is on policy sourcing claim servicing or
even for the matter of fact internal
processes a large part of our offerings
are significantly available in the
digital space and that's an area where
we're kind of investing a lot okay so
investing in digital ada has also
reduced the solvency margin requirement
for insurers that are doing crop
business and government schemes of
course that's a very small part of your
business but i understand that it will
free up almost 1400 crores for the
general insurance industry uh for icici
lombard does it free up any capital
so i think in general sonya i think from
an isis number standpoint our philosophy
has been to be sufficiently capitalized
as all times so if you see the solvency
number at 30th june we are at 2.61 the
regulatory minimum is 1.5 and the point
is absolutely right i think the amount
of crop insurance business that we do is
largely a large part of it is the
inheritance that we have from the
acquisition that we did with bharti axa
but in terms of because the amount of
crop business that we do is about 700
800 crores it doesn't kind of
significantly add up to the solvency
enhancement as a result of this change
couple one very last quick question
should a regulator be setting targets i
mean
just wanted to understand
you know
it's okay to to regulate but setting
specific target should it be regulator's
domain
so i think that's a that's a great
question so i think i think that i would
kind of again respond it in the context
of the regulatory thought process i
think the regulator's thought process is
at this point of time when you look at
different segment of insurances whether
it is motor health or even for the
matter of fact commercial lines sme
every segment of business is
significantly uninsured i mean
essentially underinsured or maybe
there's a huge opportunity that is
available for increasing penetration and
that's the drive that they are kind of
largely focusing on which is why this
entire discussion is coming through with
respect to setting off of targets and so
on and so forth i think the from our
stand the fact that the regulator is
significantly taking actions in easing
business bringing about changes in
regulation now it is for the industry to
deliver in order to make sure that we
are able to kind of meet the objective
of enhancing insurance penetration and
that's what we will be kind of focusing
on okay i got that thanks a lot for
joining us and good luck